FERNANDO RUBIO

Mechatronic Engineer

LIBEREC 46015 nando.rrb.00@gmail.com 608641504

Mechatronic Engineer Graduated from the National Engineering University (Lima, Peru), with master in Machines and Equipment Design at Technical University of Liberec (Liberec, Czech Republic) with experience in industrial design. I like to work with new technologies such as Android programming, PCB and Machines design. I participated on the Festo mechatronics olympics of Peru: Pneumatics, electropneumatics and PLC programming. Have a good background on mathematics, programming, material Engineering, and design of machines.

#readytowork

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer - Android Developer

ForceClose.pe - Lima June 2018 to August 2018

Work in the company making different Android projects and modules for clients, with a cycle of 2 week per project.

- Programming Languages used: Kotlin and Java
- Architectural pattern: MVP (Model view presenter)

Embedded Developer

MECATRONICA.PE - Lima, Lima

December 2015 to August 2018

- Developed the BlueSquid system (https://nandorrb.github.io/bluesquid/), focused on logistics and data collection.
- Developed an own PLC which helps to collect data, at low cost and send directly to the central system.
- Developed the system data monitoring and analysis software, using open source components.
- Developed Hardware products in conjunction with the company ALL ENERGY PERU SAC, oriented to the energy and natural gas market. We implement advanced technologies in innovative industrial grade products optimized for the Peruvian market. These products are competent in price, performance and durability, applying the engineering standards necessary to fill their function.

Instrumentation and Control Automation Engineer

All Energy Peru SAC - Lima, Lima February 2018 to April 2018 Project of Automation and Control of fuel supply for the generator group of the Primera Vision building (http://edificioprimeravision.com/) of the company COSAPI

I designed and implemented the fuel supply system for the First Vision building generator set. I selected the fuel level sensors for the Diesel tanks, designed the control logic (ON / OFF), designed the control board, designed the P&ID diagram, drafted the work procedures for the contracting company, programmed the board PLC control in such a way that it meets the specifications of reporting the values of the sensors via PROFINET to a BMS system.

Software Engineer / Android developer

Instituto Pacifico SA - Lima, Lima

April 2017 to October 2017

Android application development with Android Studio:

- Programming using good practices in development, correct location of packages, styles, use of gradle, appointment of classes, optimization of memory use.
- Use of design patterns: Creational, Structural, Behavioral.
- Use of web services, tabs, fragments, SQLite, SOAP, REST, etc.
- Libraries such as: Retrofit, Glide, ButterKnife, Parceler, IcePick, LeakCanary, Espresso, Robolectric, Zxing, etc.
- Use of Gradle multiproject Build to compile multiple applications at the same time.

Software Engineer

GB proyectos - San Luis, Lima

March 2016 to October 2016

Development of new functions of the GWC software for the company NEPTUNIA and CENCOSUD, this system serves as a communication bus between servers to increase decentralization, allowing servers to keep running in case one of them fails.

We automate processes through software, replacing old systems with private GWC software.

Project Engineer

SEW EuroDrive - Ate, Lima

August 2015 to January 2016

I did training in this gearmotor company for several weeks, and I have rotated through the different areas learning to assemble gearmotors and using the different products of the company.

Selection of gearmotors using the company's own software, as well as using the "Calculation and Machine Design" equations. Parameters were analyzed, such as working temperature, service factor, torque, power, working height, weather conditions, etc.

Design of electrical panels, programming of frequency inverters and PLC SEW brand.

EDUCATION

Msc. Ing. in Machines and Equipment Design

Technical University of Liberec - Liberec

2018 to 2020

Ing. in Mechatronics

Universidad Nacional de Ingenieria - Rímac, Lima 2010 to 2015

Inglés Avanzado

Asociación Cultural Peruano Británica

2010 to 2013

SKILLS

- Desarrolador Android (3 years)
- Diseño de Máquinas (3 years)
- Controladores de versiones GIT, SVN, Mercurial (3 years)
- Programacion PLC (Less than 1 year)
- SCADA (Less than 1 year)
- Diseño de Tableros electricos (Less than 1 year)
- Diseño de diagramas P&ID ISA 5.1 (Less than 1 year)
- Kotlin (Less than 1 year)
- Ingenieria de Mantenimiento (Less than 1 year)
- Android
- SDKs
- Git
- Application Development
- Java

GROUPS

Miembro de ISA - International Society of Automation

January 2017 to Present

Miembro de la Sociedad internacional de automatizacion, que desarrolla los estandares y certificaciones para la automatizacion a nivel mundial.